# **Brian Donahue**

Front-End Developer & UX Designer

Seattle, WA, USA

971-222-9892 brimwd@gmail.com brimwd.github.io/portfolio/

I've worked as a designer and developer for the last 7 years: 2 years with teams; 5 working independently. I am organized, detail-oriented, and resourceful; I create solutions that are extensible, responsive, and lean.

As a life-long artist, I've volunteered my graphic design skills for several non-profits, and a previous employer described me saying "giving back is a huge part of [my] ethos."

#### LANGUAGES and FRAMEWORKS:

HTML (HTML5), CSS (CSS3), JavaScript, jQuery, Jade, Bootstrap, LESS

#### **UX and DESIGN:**

User flows, site maps, drafting, mockups, wireframes, templating, graphic design for print and web, illustration, branding, presentations

#### TOOLS:

Sublime Text 3, Balsamiq, Axure, GitHub, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Wunderman

Web Developer, UX Designer

UX: Design work was created for an asset management service for T-Mobile

- + Created UX proposals based on existing user stories, client requests, and an alpha product version
- + Created wireframes and user flows for different classes of user
- + Documented changes and presented design proposals to the managers and development team
- + Used Microsoft TFS to track and report bugs and usability issues for the existing software

FED: Emails for Microsoft XBox & Band, and for T-Mobile

- + Developed responsive marketing emails based on Photoshop comps
- + Developed both English and Spanish-language service email templates for T-Mobile
- + Sliced and modified design comps as needed
- + Tracked bugs and language or graphical inconsistencies in TFS

November 2015 - December 2015 | Washington, United States

### **B2d Marketing**

Lead Web Developer

- + Worked as the design and strategy lead for the marketing team
- + Created campaigns for six different clients, some of which received increases on click-through rates of more than 1000% over the campaign average
- + Mentored junior developers in responsive design and development
- + Simplified code across multiple platforms and developed user stories to reduce maintenance work and improve customer engagement
- + Lead design and strategy discussions with clients and managers

October 2014 - November 2015 | Washington, United States

#### **DevDraft**

Web Developer, UX Designer

- + Developed landing pages for a Microsoft Partner Network marketing campaign
- + Contributed responsive code to improve DevDraft's website UX
- + Lead marketing strategy discussions
- + Developed user flows, user stories, and wireframes
- + Mentored one junior developer in responsive design and development

April 2015 - July 2015 | Washington, United States

#### Siren

### **UX** Designer

- + Produced user stories, user flows, wireframes, and mockups
- + Contributed to design and strategy discussions
- + Championed function over form in design planning discussions

November 2014 - December 2014 | Washington, United States

#### **Seattle Pride**

#### Visual Director

- + Worked directly with the board V.P. to plan materials and approach
- + Designed dozens of print materials including posters, flyers, badges, banners, logos, and most other marketing materials for official Seattle Pride 2014 events
- + Created vector illustrations for the beer garden map and the 40th anniversary lithograph pride poster reproduction

May 2014 - June 2014 | Washington, United States

## **Moving Worlds**

Web Developer, UX Designer

- + Created user stories, user flows, wireframes, prototypes, and templates.
- + Redesigned information organization and presentation on key pages resulting in a 30% increase in engagement for anonymous users
- + Coded templates with Bootstrap, Jade, and Less
- + Supported development with responsive design and bug fixes
- + Championed a 'mobile-first' approach
- + Created B2B print materials, presentations, and templates

April 2014 - June 2014 | Washington, United States

#### **EDUCATION**

### **University Of Iowa**

Japanese, Accounting

January 2012 - June 2012 | Iowa City, Iowa, United States

### **lowa Lakes Community College**

Graphic Design

August 2010 - December 2010 | Spirit Lake, Iowa, United States

# **University Of Iowa**

Graphic Design, Computer Science

August 2007 - December 2007 | Iowa City, Iowa, United States

### **Ringling College Of Art And Design**

Illustration

August 2006 - December 2006 | Sarasota, Florida, United States

#### **SKILLS**

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Balsamiq, Bootstrap, Branding, CSS, CSS, Drafting, GitHub, Graphic Design, HTML, Illustration, Jade, JavaScript, Jquery, Less, Mockups, Presentations, Site Maps, Sublime Text, Templating, User Flows, Ux, Wireframes